原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
第六季 第三集
权力的游戏
冷静  冷静
Easy, easy.
冷静
Easy.
你都记得什么
What do you remember?
他们用刀刺我
They stabbed me.
奥利
Olly...
他一刀捅在我心口
he put a knife in my heart.
我不该在这里
I shouldn't be here.
女士把你带了回来
The lady brought you back.
他们捅死你之后
Afterwards, after they stabbed you,
你死了之后  去了哪里
after you died, where did you go?
你看到了什么
What did you see?
没有
Nothing.
什么都没有
There was nothing at all.
光之王让你回来必有原因
The Lord let you come back for a reason.
史坦尼斯不是预言中的王子
Stannis was not the prince who was promised,
但必须有一个王子
but someone has to be.
能让我们单独说几句吗
Could you give us a moment?
你死过
You were dead.
现在又活过来
And now you're not.
我都觉得这是纯他妈见鬼
That's completely fucking mad, seems to me.
你是什么感受  我只能想象
I can only imagine how it seems to you.
我做了我认为正确的事
I did what I thought was right.
却为此被人杀死
And I got murdered for it.
现在我又回来了
And now I'm back.
为什么
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
或许我们永远不会知道
Maybe we'll never know.
有什么关系呢
What does it matter?
你只管继续
You go on.
一息尚存  就继续战斗下去
You fight for as long as you can.
尽你全力收拾这片烂摊子
You clean up as much of the shit as you can.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know how to do that.
我以为我知道  可是
I thought I did, but...
我失败了
I failed.
很好
Good.
那就屡败屡战
Now go fail again.
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：Silmar 草草 潇湘月影
■
翻译：欧沈娜 盐湖凉开水 ET外星人
校对：Silmar   顾问：屈畅(ccxx)
时间轴：崽猪 加森 aaaBao Avis
后期：吉吉·波顿  总监：泰斯·雪诺
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
他们以为你是个神
They think you're some kind of god.
死而复生的人
The man who returned from the dead.
我不是神
I'm not a god.
我知道
I know that.
我瞧见你的小鸟了
I saw your pecker.
哪有神的鸟会那么小
What kind of god would have a pecker that small?
你的眼睛还是棕色
Your eyes are still brown.
你还是你吗
Is that still you in there?
我想是的
I think so.
先别急着烧我尸体
Hold off on burning my body for now.
都会说笑了
That's funny.
你确定你还是你吗
You sure that's still you in there?
你还好吗
You all right?
还好  我没事
Yes. Yes, I'm fine.
我有没讲过  我一直以为海跟看是同一个字
Did I ever tell you I used to think the sea was called the see
因为一眼看去都是水  没有别的东西
because it was nothing but water as far as the eye could see?
应该不是
I don't think so.
海  看
Sea, see.
拼写不同  可是发音都一样
They're spelled different, but they sound the same.
对  是一样的
Yeah, they do.
这显然是我学识字之前的事了
It was before I learned how to read, obviously.
山姆  你要吐吗
Sam, are you going to be sick?
不会很久了  我们马上就到南方了
Won't be long. We'll be in the south soon.
我很期待看到旧镇
I'm excited to see Oldtown.
船长说那是维斯特洛最美的城市
Captain says it's the most beautiful city in Westeros.
你又要吐了吗
Are you going to vomit again?
不不不不
No. No, no, no.
学城不收女人
The Citadel doesn't admit women.
那里没有你和小山姆的容身之处
There won't be a place for you there or for Little Sam.
黑城堡我都待过了  那里也不许有女人的
I stayed at Castle Black. There's no women allowed there.
学城不是黑城堡
The Citadel isn't Castle Black.
那里没有琼恩·雪诺和伊蒙师父帮我通融
I don't have a Jon Snow or Maester Aemon to help me bend the rules.
那我就留在旧镇
I'll stay in Oldtown, then.
你一个人
By yourself?
带着婴儿  身无分文
With a baby and no money?
要是不去旧镇  你这是带我去哪儿
So if we're not going to Oldtown, where are you taking me?
去我家
To my home.
角陵
Horn Hill.
我父亲他...我父亲
My father's-- well, my father,
但我母亲很可亲  妹妹也好
but my mother's a kind woman and my sister's lovely.
她们会照顾你们母子
They'll take care of you both.
"你去哪儿我就去哪儿"
"Wherever you go, I go, too."
这是你说的
That's what you said.
我那样说是希望你和小山姆安全
I said that because I want you and Little Sam to be safe.
我只希望你们平安
That's all I want--
我要当学士  好在需要的时候帮助琼恩
to become a maester so I can help Jon when the time comes
也是为了你们能平安
so you'll be safe.
我们  还有世界上所有人都能平安
Us and everyone else in the world.
我不管别人怎样
I don't care about them.
好吧  也是管的  但我并不在乎
Well, no, I do, but I don't really.
我在乎你和他
I care about you and him.
我知道  山姆
I know that, Sam.
他也知道
And he does, too.
你是唯一一个在乎我们的人
You're the only one who ever has.
如果你认为这样最好
If you think it's for the best,
我们信你
we trust you.
你丢东西砸我转身就走  我心里还会好过些
I'd feel better if you threw something at me and stormed off.
我永远不会那样对我儿子的父亲
I'd never do that to the father of my son.
是我父亲
That's my father.
他身边的是霍兰·黎德  梅拉的父亲
The man beside him is Howland Reed, meera's father.
亚瑟·戴恩爵士
Ser Arthur Dayne.
拂晓神剑
The Sword of the Morning.
父亲说亚瑟是他见过的最优秀的剑士
Father said he was the best swordsman he ever saw.
史塔克大人
Lord Stark.
我在三叉戟河上没看见你
I looked for you on the Trident.
我们没去
We weren't there.
要是我们在场
Your friend the usurper
你的篡夺者朋友此时已经入土了
would lie beneath the ground if we had been.
疯王已死
The Mad King is dead.
雷加也倒卧沙场
Rhaegar lies beneath the ground.
怎么没去保护你们的王子
Why weren't you there to protect your prince?
王子要我们守在这里
Our prince wanted us here.
我妹妹在哪儿
Where's my sister?
祝你在接下来的战争中好运
I wish you good fortune in the wars to come.
现在战争开始
And now it begins.
不
No.
战争于此终结
Now it ends.
他比我父亲厉害
He's better than my father.
厉害多了
Far better.
但父亲击败了他
But Father beat him.
是吗
Did he?
我知道他赢了
I know he did.
这故事我听过上千次
Heard the story a thousand times.
他从背后偷袭了他
He stabbed him in the back.
塔里有什么
What's in the tower?
今天就到这儿吧
That's enough for one day.
我们改日再来
We'll visit again another time.
-我想看他去了哪  -该走了
- I want to see where he's going. - Time to go.
父亲
Father!
你为什么要这样
Why did you do that?
带我回去  我想回去
Take me back there. I want to go back.
不行
No.
-他听到我了  -或许吧
- He heard me. - Maybe.
-或许他只是听到了风声  -他听到我了
- Maybe he heard the wind. - He heard me.
历史已经写就  墨凝于纸
The past is already written. The ink is dry.
塔里是什么
What's in that tower?
我想回去
I want to go back there.
我说过很多次了  在你不该待的地方待太久
I've told you many times, stay too long where you don't belong
你将无法回来
and you will never return.
我为什么要回来
Why do I want to return?
好再做个残废吗
So I can be a cripple again?
好跟长在树里的老头子说话吗
So I can talk to an old man in a tree?
你以为我想在这里枯坐千年
You think I wanted to sit here for 1,000 years
远远看着世界
watching the world from a distance
任凭树根穿过身体
as the roots grew through me?
那你为什么还要在这
So why did you?
我在等你
I was waiting for you.
我不想成为你
I don't want to be you.
这不怪你
I don't blame you.
你不会永远待在这里
You won't be here forever.
你不会成为长在树里的老头
You won't be an old man in a tree.
但在离开之前
But before you leave,
你必须学习
you must learn.
学什么
Learn what?
一切
Everything.
伟大的卡丽熙  赶紧走
欢迎回家  卡丽熙
下去吧
你们干什么
放开我
我要砍了你们的头
你们犯了个错误
你们会后悔的
我是卡奥的妻子
我们知道你是谁
我记得你吃骏马的心
卓戈卡奥死后  你为什么没来找我们
因为我是风暴降生丹妮莉丝
解放者
弥林女王  龙之母
我不该跟你们待在一起
你的确曾是伟大卡奥的妻子
你以为有你在他身边  他能征服世界
但他没有
我也曾是伟大卡奥的妻子
萨沃卡奥
我也以为有我在他身边  他能征服世界
你还年轻
我们都曾年轻
但我们都理解这世道
你也会理解的
如果你有幸留在我们身边的话
要不我还能去哪
每个卡丽熙都会成为多希卡林
没错  一旦她们的卡奥死去
但你去过外面的世界
那是禁忌
所有卡拉萨都回来
他们将决定去洗劫哪座城市  奴役哪个部落
现在他们还得决定  要如何处置卓戈卡奥的银发遗孀
如果你走运  就能留在我们这里  龙之母
那是你眼下最好的结局
真不知你们一身皮甲怎么挨得住
I don't know how you stand it in all that leather.
麻烦你们下去
If we could have the room.
你今天真美  亲爱的  真的
You look lovely today, my dear. You really do.
爬那么多级阶梯不留一滴汗  你怎么做到的
How you climbed all those steps without breaking a sweat.
如果你要折磨我
If you're going to torture me,
赶紧把他们叫回来开始吧
just call them back and get on with it.
我不折磨人
I am not a torturer.
尽管很多人都是活该受折磨
Though it so often is what people deserve.
而且折磨的确能让我得到答案
And it does provide answers.
但通常都是错误的答案
But they're usually the wrong answers.
我的职责是找到正确的答案
My job is to find the right answers.
你知道我怎么找答案吗
Do you know how I do that?
我让人们快活
I do it by making people happy.
我很乐意让你快活  瓦拉
I'd like to make you happy, Vala.
那是你的名字  对不对  瓦拉
That's your name, isn't it, Vala?
没关系
That's all right.
我知道你是谁  做了什么
I know who you are and what you've done.
你做过很多事
You've done a lot.
你出卖身体是有原因的
You've sacrificed your body for a cause,
比大多数人高尚得多
which is more than most people do.
你帮助鹰身女妖之子谋杀无垢者
And you've helped the Sons of the Harpy murder the Unsullied
和次子团
and the Second Sons.
无垢者和次子团是异邦战士
The Unsullied and the Second Sons are foreign soldiers
跟随异邦女王而来
brought here by a foreign queen
摧毁我们的城市和历史
to destroy our city and our history.
我明白
I understand.
在你看来
Well, that makes perfect sense
非常有道理
from your perspective.
但我有不同观点
I have a different perspective, of course.
我认为
I think it's important
你必须站在我的角度看问题
that you try to see things from my perspective
正如我站在你的角度看问题
just as I will try to see them from yours.
因为只有这样
Because that is the only way
我才让你和多姆都快活
that I can make you and Dom happy.
多姆  是这样发音吗
That is how you pronounce it-- Dom?
抱歉我不太会讲你们的语言
I'm afraid I don't really speak the language.
真是英俊的小男孩
Such a handsome boy.
一双棕色的大眼睛  当心被姑娘们吃了
Those big, brown eyes. Good luck keeping the ladies away.
是啊  你真是解放者  不是吗
Yes, you're a true liberator, aren't you?
你不折磨我  只会用我的儿子威胁我
You won't torture me, you'll just threaten my son.
孩子是无辜的
Children are blameless.
我决不会伤害他们
I have never hurt them.
你儿子眼下没有危险
Your boy is in no immediate danger,
这点我可以保证
this I swear to you.
但我悄悄说一句  亲爱的
But between us, dear,
你曾共谋杀害女王的战士
you did conspire to kill the Queen's soldiers.
我们都清楚这该当何罪
We both know the penalty for that crime.
可怜的多姆要是没了母亲可怎么办
How will poor Dom get on without his mother?
何况他还有呼吸疾病
And with his breathing problem.
如果我说了  他们会杀了我
If I tell you anything, they'll kill me.
不死在你手里  也会死在他们手里
So either you kill me or they do.
是啊  从你的角度  这是一个问题
Yes, from your perspective, this is a problem.
不过还有第三条路
There is a third option, though.
明天有艘驶往潘托斯的船
A ship leaving tomorrow for Pentos.
我已经为一个女人和她的儿子订了船票
I've already booked passage for a woman and her young son.
我甚至会给你一袋银币  帮你重新开始
I'll even throw in a bag of silver to help you start again.
不过恐怕得劳烦
Though I'm afraid we'll have to ask
一位穿皮甲的朋友回来帮着搬
one of our leather-clad friends back in to carry it.
我是搬不动的
Far too heavy for me.
船拂晓起航
The boat sails at dawn.
你得现在决定
You need to decide now.
是跟多姆一起开始新生活
A new life for you and Dom
还是...
or...
等待的时候该做点什么
What should we do while we wait?
打发时间  该做点什么
To pass the time, what should we do?
我们谈点什么
What should we talk about?
你会十九种语言
You speak 19 languages.
一定时不时会用来聊聊天吧
You must occasionally use some of them to talk about things.
你们两个相处了那么久
You two, you spend a great deal of time together.
如果我不在  你俩会聊什么
What would you be talking about if I weren't here?
巡逻
Patrol.
我跟无垢者一起巡逻的时候
When I am going on patrol with the Unsullied.
路上看到了什么
What we see on patrol.
抓到了什么
Who we captured on patrol.
很好  非常好
That's good. That's very good.
但那是汇报
But that's a report.
我问的是聊天
I was thinking more of a conversation.
一位智者曾经说过  真正的历史
A wise man once said the true history of the world
是高雅房间里的伟大谈话史
is the history of great conversations in elegant rooms.
这是谁说的
Who said this?
我
Me.
刚才说的
Just now.
好吧  不聊天了
All right, no conversations.
我们玩个游戏
Let's play a game.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
你们两个从来没玩过游戏吗
You don't play games, either one of you, ever?
游戏是孩子玩的
Games are for children.
克拉兹尼主人偶尔会让我们玩游戏
My master Kraznys would sometimes make us play games.
看  好的开始
There, that's a start.
-只有女孩  -不不不
- Only the girls. - No, no, no.
不是那种  当然不是
Not that. Of course not that.
纯洁的游戏  有趣的游戏
Innocent games. Fun games.
喝酒游戏
Drinking games.
我们不喝酒
We do not drink.
现在喝了
Until you do.
好吧  不喝酒
All right. No drinking.
不喝酒也能玩
We can play without drinking.
这是很棒的游戏  我发明的
It's a wonderful game. I invented it.
规则是这样
Here's how it works.
我描述你们的过去
I make a statement about your past.
如果我说错了  我喝酒
If I'm wrong, I drink.
如果我说对了
And if I'm right--
还是得喝酒才能玩
maybe we can't play without drinking.
你够慢的
Oh, you took your time.
抱歉
Sorry.
我在忙着调查鹰身女妖之子的资助者
I was busy learning who funds the Sons of the Harpy.
-这事急不来  -你查到了吗
- Some things you can't rush. - You found out?
阿斯塔波的善主
The Good Masters of Astapor
和渊凯的贤主
and the Wise Masters of Yunkai.
还有瓦兰提斯朋友的帮助
With help from their friends in Volantis.
你看
You see?
根本不必担心本城的叛乱
You don't even have to worry about the local rebellion.
我们只消担心
We only have to worry about
那三个花钱资助叛乱的异域富国
the three rich foreign cities paying for it.
我们曾征服过阿斯塔波和渊凯
We conquered Astapor and Yunkai once.
我们将再次征服它们  处死奴隶主
We will do it again and execute the Masters.
如果无垢者前往征服阿斯塔波和渊凯
If the Unsullied march off to reconquer Astapor and Yunkai,
谁来守卫弥林的自由民
who will remain to defend the free people of Meereen?
如果我们不去战斗  如何能阻止他们
If we do not fight them, how can we stop them?
我们做不到
We cannot.
奴隶主只会说一种语言
The Masters speak only one language.
他们对我说过许多年
They spoke it to me for many years.
我对它比母语还熟悉
I know it better than my mother tongue.
如果要他们顺从我们  我们必须以牙还牙
If we want them to hear us, we must speak it back to them.
这会是他们听到的最后一句话
May it be the last thing they ever hear.
你也许是对的
You may be right.
所以我们会与他们作战吗
So we will fight them?
-可能吧  -可能
- Possibly. - Possibly?
我们这是在商议
It's a conversation.
告诉我  你的小小鸟能给
Tell me, can your little birds get a message
阿斯塔波的善主  阿斯塔波的贤主
to the Good Masters of Astapor, the Wise Masters of Yunkai,
和瓦兰提斯的奴隶主带句话吗
and benevolent enslavers of Volantis?
当然可以  人也许易变
Of course. Men can be fickle,
但小小鸟永远值得信任
but birds I always trust.
你的眼睛看上去好多了  亚瑟
Your eye looks much better, Arthur.
你妈妈的下巴情况如何
How's your mother's jaw?
好多了
Better.
你爸爸呢
And your father?
没人看见他
No one's seen him.
再也不会有人看见了
And no one will.
恢复得还不错
That worked out rather nicely.
瓦里斯大人还会回来吗
Will Lord Varys ever come back?
我想不会了
I don't think so.
你想他吗
Do you miss him?
他是个好人
He was nice.
他叫我们小小鸟儿
He called us his little birds.
他给我们糖吃
He gave us sweets.
既然提到这个
It's funny you should mention that.
猜猜看我今天找到了什么
Guess what I happened to find today.
多恩的糖梅
Candied plums from Dorne.
记住  如果你们的朋友
Now remember, if any of your friends
喜欢糖果或者需要帮助  随时来找我
like sweets or need help, they can always come to me.
我需要的回报只有一些悄悄话
All I need in return are whispers.
不用害怕
No need to be afraid.
这是格雷果爵士
This is Ser Gregor.
我的朋友也是他的朋友
He's friends with all my friends.
走吧
Run along now.
瓦里斯的小小鸟儿
Varys's little birds?
现在是您的了  陛下
Your little birds now, Your Grace.
你到底对他做了什么
What did you do to him exactly?
你每次都支支吾吾的
I haven't been able to get a clear answer.
就一些事情啦
Oh, a number of things.
他明白我们在说什么吗
Does he understand what we're saying?
我是说  他以前就
I mean, to the extent that he ever understood
不太听得全别人讲话
complete sentences in the first place.
他懂得足够多
He understands well enough.
那就告诉他  冲进大教堂
So tell him to march into the sept
像砸甜瓜一样砸碎大麻雀的头
and crush the High Sparrow's head like a melon.
大麻雀周围有数百战争之子保护
The High Sparrow has hundreds of Faith Militant surrounding him.
格雷果爵士无法以一敌百
Ser Gregor can't face them all.
他也不需要
And he won't have to.
他只需面对一人
He'll only have to face one.
教团下达正式指控了吗
Has the Faith leveled official charges yet?
还没
Not yet.
真期待这场比武审判
That is one trial by combat I look forward to watching.
不要止步于君临
Don't stop at the city.
我想要小小鸟儿飞到多恩
I want little birds in Dorne,
飞到高庭  飞到北境
in Highgarden, in the North.
如果有人想把我们的一切掠为己有
If someone is planning on making our losses their gains,
我要知道
I want to hear it.
如果有人在嘲笑王后
If someone is laughing at the queen
裸身游街  遭人泼粪
who walked naked through the streets covered in shit,
我要知道
I want to hear.
我要知道他们是谁
I want to know who they are.
我要知道他们在哪
I want to know where they are.
瓦里斯大人已经够坏了  而科本更甚
As bad as Lord Varys was, Qyburn is worse.
我警告过他们  警告过
I told them all. I told them.
他既自大又危险
He's arrogant, dangerous.
不会有人平白无故被赶出学城
You don't get thrown out of the Citadel without good reason.
没人听从我的建议
And no one listened to my advice.
我们才沦落至此
So here we are.
他对格雷果·克里冈做的事
And what he's done to Gregor Clegane
真是造孽
is an abomination.
我们从未批准过这项实验
We never sanctioned this experiment.
我觉得为了我们的共同利益
I for one think it will be in our best interest
应该把这个怪物毁...
to have the beast dest--
-您有何贵干  -你为什么在这里
- Can I help you? - Why are you here?
-我母亲  -我是受邀前来  亲爱的
- My mother-- - I was invited, my dear,
解决几件麻烦事
to help deal with several troublesome issues,
比如王后被囚一事
such as the queen's imprisonment.
谢谢您提及此事
Thank you for bringing it up.
早该为我遭受的欺辱做出反击
It's well past time we addressed the abuses I endured.
玛格丽才是王后
Margaery is the queen.
您不是王后
You are not the queen
因为国王不是你丈夫
because you're not married to the king.
我理解这些事
I do appreciate these things
在您家里可能会有点混淆
can get a bit confusing in your family.
这是御前会议
This is a small council meeting.
您并不是御前会议的一员
You have no position on the small council.
我是御林铁卫队长
I'm the Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
御林铁卫队长
The Lord Commander of the Kingsguard
在御前会议总有一席之地吧
does have a position on the small council.
派席尔大学士  你认可这样的说法吗
Grand Maester Pycelle, would you sanction that statement?
这个
Well, um...
杰洛德·高塔爵士
I would say Ser Gerold Hightower
是疯王的御前会议成员
had a seat on the Mad King's council.
当然了  那是在疯王时代
Of course, that was the Mad King.
劳勃国王对此有不同的看法
King Robert saw things differently.
还有乔佛里国王...
And King-- -
弥赛菈的死怎么说  叔叔
What about Myrcella's death, Uncle?
你认为你血亲的死
Do you consider the murder of your own blood
是个棘手的问题吗
a troublesome issue?
杀死弥赛菈的同一群女人
The same women who murdered Myrcella
已经推翻了马泰尔家族的统治并控制了多恩
have overthrown House Martell and taken control of Dorne.
我们有很多话题需要讨论
We've got a lot to discuss.
我们所有人一起
All of us together.
而且看情况你们没办法赶走我们  那就开始讨论吧
And seeing as you cannot make us leave, we best get on with it.
是啊  我们没办法把你们赶走
No, we cannot make you leave.
而你们也没办法留住我们
And you cannot make us stay.
除非你想让那个怪物把我们都杀掉
Not unless you're gonna have that thing murder us all.
陛下
Your Grace.
我的母亲想看看她女儿的长眠之处
My mother would like to see her daughter's final resting place.
非常抱歉  陛下
I'm sorry, Your Grace.
目前还不可以
That's not possible. Not yet.
什么时候可以
When will it be possible?
当她彻底赎罪时
When she's fully atoned for her sins.
你剪掉她的头发还将她
You cut off her hair and marched her naked
当着全城的面全裸游行示众
through the streets in front of the whole city.
那不算彻底赎罪吗
That wasn't the full atonement?
不
No.
她必须在七名修士面前接受审判
She must stand trial before seven septons
这样我们才能了解她罪过的真相
so we can learn the true extent of her sins.
我要你允许她去看弥赛菈的长眠之处
I want you to let her see Myrcella's resting place.
我是国王
I am the king.
你是
You are.
国王对你有何意义
And what does that mean to you?
国王对我意义重大
It means a great deal to me.
王权和信仰
The Crown and the Faith
是世界的两大支柱
are the twin pillars of the world.
你知道这句话是谁告诉我的吗
Do you know who told me that?
正是你的母亲
Your mother.
我那不洁的母亲吗
My mother who is unclean?
我那在被你折磨过后
My mother who still needs
仍需赎罪的母亲吗
to atone after all you've put her through?
你认为圣母是如何降临人间的
How do you think the Mother Above first came to us?
世间的男女
How did men and women
是如何第一次感受圣母的存在的
first come to feel the Mother's presence, hmm?
是通过他们自己的母亲
It was through their own mothers.
瑟曦还有很多谎言  你知道的
There's a great deal of falsehood in Cersei. You know that.
但当她谈到你的时候  圣母之爱的光芒就掩盖了所有的谎言
But when she speaks of you, the Mother's love outshines it all.
她对你的爱
Her love for you is more real
比世间任何事物都更加真实
than anything else in this world
因为这份爱不是来自于这个世界的
because it doesn't come from this world.
但是你明白
But you know that.
你已经感受到了
You've felt it.
你见过她跟你说话的样子
You've seen her when she talks to you.
是的
Yes.
这是个伟大的恩赐
It's a great gift.
我从未有过如此福份
One I never had.
嫉妒
Envy.
是我应该忏悔的另一项罪过
One more thing for me to atone for.
陛下  我可以...
Your Grace, do you-- may I?
你介意我坐下吗
Do you mind?
我的膝盖受不了了
It's my knees.
当然可以
Of course.
你的母亲踏上赎罪之旅
When your mother made her walk of atonement,
是为了能够回到你的身边
she did it to get back to you.
我还是不明白  她已经受了那么多苦
I still don't understand why you want to put her
你为什么还要让她忍受更多
through any more than she's already endured.
这并非我所愿  而是诸神之意
It's not what I want. It's what the gods want.
诸神将旨意告诉我们
They make their will known to us and it's up to us
来决定是否接受的是我们自己
to either accept or reject it.
请坐
Please.
如果我们想公正善良
If we're to be just and good,
我们就得接受  不管你是草民还是国王
then we accept it, all of us, even kings.
一位真正的领导者会听从最智慧的建议
A true leader avails himself of the wisest counsel he can.
没人比诸神更加智慧
And no one is wiser than the gods.
我外祖父说过类似的话
My grandfather once said something similar.
除了跟诸神相关的那部分
Except for the part about the gods.
不管他是否意识到  诸神的旨意通过他显达
The gods worked through him whether he knew it or not.
正如诸神的旨意也通过你母亲显达
As they work through your mother.
我们每个人心中都有善良的部分
There's so much good in all of us.
我们能做的就是帮助彼此将其发掘出来
The best we can do is to help each other bring it out.
你是谁
Who are you?
无名之辈
No one.
你来到这里之前是谁
Who were you before you came here?
艾莉亚·史塔克
Arya Stark.
跟我说说艾莉亚·史塔克的家人
Tell me about Arya Stark's family.
她的父亲是艾德·史塔克
Her father was Eddard Stark.
她的母亲是凯特琳·史塔克
Her mother was Catelyn Stark.
她有一个姐姐  珊莎
She had one sister, Sansa,
还有四个兄弟
and four brothers.
三个兄弟
Three brothers.
罗柏  布兰  瑞肯
Robb, Bran, Rickon.
还有一个异母哥哥琼恩
And a half-brother Jon.
他们现在在哪里
And where are they now?
据女孩所知他们可能都死了
They may be dead for all a girl knows.
跟我说说猎狗
Tell me about the Hound.
他也死了
Also dead.
艾莉亚·史塔克将他留下等死  他在她的名单上
Arya Stark left him to die. He was on her list.
他已经不在名单上了
He was not on her list anymore.
她已经将他在名单上除掉了
She had taken him off it.
为什么  她不想让他死了吗
Why? Didn't she want him dead any longer?
她想  她也不想
She did and she did not.
她听起来很迷茫
She sounds confused.
是的  她迷茫过
Yes, she was.
还有谁在艾莉亚·史塔克的有趣小名单上
Who else was on Arya Stark's funny little list?
詹姆·兰尼斯特
Cersei Lannister.
格雷果·克里冈
Gregor Clegane.
瓦德·佛雷
Walder Frey.
名单很短
That's a short list.
你要杀的人不可能那么少
That can't be everyone you want to kill.
你确定没有漏掉谁吗
Are you sure you're not forgetting someone?
你想女孩告诉你谁的名字
Which name would you like a girl to speak?
女孩说出自己的名字
If a girl tells me her name,
我就把双眼还给她
I will give her eyes back.
女孩没有名字
A girl has no name.
过来
Come.
若女孩真是无名之辈
If a girl is truly no one,
她就无需害怕
she has nothing to fear.
你是谁
Who are you?
无名之辈
No one.
安柏家以忠诚闻名
The Umbers are a famously loyal house.
以对史塔克家忠诚而闻名
Famously loyal to the Starks.
你呢  卡史塔克伯爵
And you, Lord Karstark.
你们跟史塔克家血脉相连  不是吗
Your people share blood with the Starks, don't they?
但事到如今  时代变了
But here we are. Times change.
我父亲成为北境守护时
When my father became Warden of the North,
你的家族拒绝效忠
your house refused to pledge their banners.
你父亲是个懦夫
Your father was a cunt.
我亲爱的父亲  北境...
My beloved father, the Warden...
你父亲是个懦夫  所以你才杀了他
Your father was a cunt and that's why you killed him.
我也可能会杀我父亲
I might have done the same to my father
不过他帮了我的忙自己先死了
if he hadn't have done me the favor of dying on his own.
我父亲是被敌人毒死的
My father was poisoned by our enemies.
你为什么来临冬城  安柏大人
Why have you come to Winterfell, Lord Umber?
私生子琼恩·雪诺带领一支野人军队越过长城
The bastard Jon Snow led an army of wildlings past the Wall.
我们比你们这些混蛋都更靠北
We're farther north than any of you fuckers.
野人南下  我们首当其冲
Wildlings come down, we always have to fight them first.
我喜欢打野人  一辈子都在打
I like fighting wildlings. Been doing it all my life.
但这次数量太多  我们无法独自抗衡
But there are too many of them for us to beat back alone.
所以你是来寻求帮助的
So now you've come seeking help?
我们要互相帮助
We need to help each other.
天气越冷
The colder it gets,
那些混蛋就会越往南边走
the farther south those goat fuckers will roam.
他们不久就会来到这里
Won't take them long to get here.
你以为一群野人就能拿下临冬城吗
You think a horde of wildlings can take Winterfell?
如果有琼恩·雪诺带领  也许能
If they get Jon Snow leading them, maybe.
他比我们都熟悉这片地方
He knows this place better than we ever will.
向波顿家族效忠
Pledge your banners to House Bolton.
承认我是北境守护
Swear loyalty to me as Warden of the North
我们就可以一起打败那个私生子
and we will fight together to destroy the bastard
和他的野人朋友
and all his wildling friends.
我不会吻你的爪子
I'm not kissing your fucking hand.
根据传统  封臣当向封君下跪
Traditionally a bannerman kneels before his lord.
我也不会下跪
I'm not doing that either.
我为什么要相信一个不尊重传统的人
Why would I trust a man who won't honor tradition?
你父亲尊重传统
Your father honored tradition.
向罗柏·史塔克下跪
Knelt for Robb Stark.
称他为北境之王
Called him King of the North.
罗柏·史塔克相信你父亲是信对了吗
Was Robb Stark right to trust your father?
看来我们是走入僵局了
Then it appears we're at a bit of an impasse.
去他的下跪  去他的誓言
Fuck kneeling and fuck oaths.
我给你们带了礼物
I've got a gift for you.
我希望是个女孩  红发的最好
A girl, I hope. I prefer redheads.
女的  没错
A girl, aye.
野女人
A wild one.
我喜欢野女人
I like them wild.
还有男孩  年轻美好
And the boy, nice and young.
是卡史塔克喜欢的模样
The way Karstark likes them.
这是谁
Who's this?
瑞肯·史塔克
Rickon Stark.
我怎么知道这就是瑞肯·史塔克
How do I know that's Rickon Stark?
欢迎回家  史塔克大人
Welcome home, Lord Stark.
是时候了
It's time.
若有什么遗言  现在说吧
If you have any last words, now is the time.
你不该还活着
You shouldn't be alive.
这不对
It's not right.
杀我也不对
Neither was killing me.
我母亲仍住在白港
My mother's still living at White Harbor.
你能写信给她吗
Could you write her?
告诉她我是与野人对抗战死的
Tell her I died fighting the wildlings.
我有两个选择  总司令
I had a choice, Lord Commander.
背叛你或背叛守夜人
Betray you or betray the Night's Watch.
你让野人军队踏入我们的土地
You brought an army of wildlings into our lands.
一群杀人犯和强盗
An army of murderers and raiders.
若明知结果如此  再让我选一次
If I had to do it all over knowing where I'd end up,
我希望我能再次做出正确的选择
I pray I'd make the right choice again.
我相信你会的  艾里沙爵士
I'm sure you would, Ser Alliser.
我战斗过  我输了
I fought, I lost.
现在我可以安息了
Now I rest.
但你  雪诺大人
But you, Lord Snow,
你会穷尽一生为他们战斗
you'll be fighting their battles forever.
我们应该烧掉尸体
We should burn the bodies.
你去吧
You should.
这件衣服要我怎么处理
What do you want me to do with this?
穿上它
Wear it.
烧了它
Burn it.
随便你
Whatever you want.
黑城堡是你的了
You have Castle Black.
■
人人美剧APP
看美剧就来人人美剧
更新快 无删减
最大最全的美剧平台
扫码即刻下载
Zimuzu特别推荐
■
各大应用市场均可下载
我的守望于斯结束
My watch is ended.